Justin: You’re thinking of taking a vacation or traveling somewhere nice,
but there are so many different ways of traveling,
and thousands of places to go.
Where do you start?
Why not follow these three simple steps to find the right vacation for you?
Step one. Think about what you want to do on your vacation.
The first thing people usually try to decide is where they want to go,
but it’s probably better to start by thinking about what you want to do.
Do you want to relax?
Then think about how you relax.
For example, do you like reading or doing yoga,
or do you like doing something more active?
Do you want to visit an exciting new city,
or see some scenery and animals that are different from where you live?
Seeing something completely new is
a great way to forget about your normal life.
Do you want to go on an adventure?
Perhaps you’re dreaming about climbing Mount Fuji
or living in Kenya with the Maasai people.
You could use your vacation to make one of those dreams come true.
Do you want to learn something new?
Not everybody wants to sit in a classroom learning a new language
or be in a kitchen learning to cook when they’re on vacation,
but some people love it.
And nowadays you can take courses in many countries
and experience a different culture at the same time.
So now, step two.
Think about the people you’re going to go with.
Are they family or friends?
Do they have children?
What do they want to do?
People have different needs and interests,
and if you’re all going to enjoy the vacation,
you need to make sure you all want the same things.
But if what you really want to do is to meet new people,
maybe it would be better to travel alone.
And finally, step three.
Think about good vacations you had in the past.
Why were they good?
Maybe it was the people you were with.
Maybe it was something you learned, or an experience you had.
What can you repeat from those vacations?
Of course, there are always other things you need to consider,
like how much money you can spend,
and how much time you can be away.
But, first, follow these three steps,
and then you’re ready to start thinking about where you want to go!